## Deborah UWIMBABAZI, M.A, CTFL, CTFL-PT

#### **SUMMARY**

A certified software tester with two years of work experience in manual testing, automation testing, management and organization of software testing project and tech (Software testing) and Work Readiness facilitation, training and Solution Focus Coaching. Hold a Master's degree in Electronics and Communication Engineering. Skilled in problem-solving, critical thinking and management.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Software Project Manager | GHC Fellow at Health Builders (July 2021-present) Kigali-Rwanda, August 2019-October 2020

- Support Health Builders by adapting and digitizing existing health centers performance evaluation tools.
- Conduct quality assurance processes on the digitized performance evaluation tools
- ❖ Conduct a review of Health Builders M&E system and requirements analysis.
- ❖ Assist in the assessment of project and health facilities training needs in IT and participate in system applications trainings
- ❖ Assist in developing simple tools to automate certain processes at Health Builders and in health facilities and provide support in data management.
- Develop a plan to record software documentation and best practices

#### QA Software Test Engineer at Muraho Technology (Nov 2019 – July 2021)

- Performing requirements analysis for both Websites and mobile apps and writing Test Plans
- Designing functional test cases and executing them manually
- Performing automation testing with any of the tools listed on the left side under the "Automation Testing Tools" section
- Set up a test strategy that led to successful API testing
- ❖ Performing manual and automated API testing with tools such as Postman or Cypress
- Performing continuous testing for both frontend and backend (including APIs) during continuous integration
- Performing client-side and server-side performance testing (Load and Stress Testing)
- Detecting, reporting and tracking software bugs using JIRA
- Drafting reports during testing including a Test Summary Report and Project Final Report
- Documentation using JIRA and Confluence.

## Coach, Facilitator and Trainer at Muraho Technology (April – June 2021)

❖ Train and coach Junior testers about Work Readiness Competencies, Software Testing, and Job Placement using Solution Focused approach

#### QA Software Tester Intern at Muraho Technology (March 2019 - Nov 2019)

- ❖ Learning QA Software Testing and Project Management.
- Learning how to write test cases and bug reporting.
- Detecting and reporting software defects.
- Analyzing user stories and requirements for validity and feasibility.
- Executing all levels of testing (Component, Integration, System, and Acceptance).
- Designing and developing test automation scripts as needed.

## EDUCATION BACKGROUND

- Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunication, Beijing (China)
  Master's Degree, Electronics and Communication Engineering
  Sept 2016 July 2018
- ❖ UR-College of Science and Technology, Kigali (Rwanda) Bachelor Degree, Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering Nov 2013 – July 2016

#### CONTACT INFORMATION

Gisozi – Gasabo Kigali-Rwanda Tel:+250788352535 kagajudebby@gmail.com

## PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Leadership
- Project Management
- Planning and organization
- Critical thinking
- Problem-solving

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Attention to detail
- Willing to learn
- Team Player
- ➢ Good Communicator
- > Fast Learner
- Ownership
- Adaptability
- > Integrity

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ▶ JAVA & JAVASCRIPT
- > Python
- > HTML & CSS
- > MySQL
- ➤ PHP

### **AUTOMATION TESTING TOOLS**

- Cypress
- Ruby
- Selenium Web-driver
- > TestNG
- ➤ BDD Cucumber,
- > Appium Studio,
- Postman, K6, JMeter

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- ASTQB Foundation Level Certificate
- > ISTQB Performance Testing
- ➤ QA Basics and Work Readiness Certificate
- ➤ ISTQB Foundation Course & Project Management

## LANGUAGE SPOKEN

- > English-Advanced
- > French-Medium
- > Kinyarwanda-Native
- > Chinese-Basic

## REFERENCES

#### Michael Pucci, PhD

Education Innovation Director Muraho Technology

pucci@muraho.tech

## Ishimwe Jean de Dieu

Operations Quality Lead at Babyl Rwanda

ishimweja@gmail.com